hey everyone welcome back to this Tosca
automation playlist and today I am going
to talk about a common issue which we
face during our test Automation and how
we can dissolve this in Tosca
so the scenario is when you have
Elements which have got common
properties how do you identify these
elements now one way we have already
seen is to use different identification
mechanisms available in Tosca like you
can identify by anchor by image or by
index but what if you don't want to use
any of these options right and there is
another option which you can Implement
right at a test case level okay so we'll
see how you can do this
and our scenario is on this particular
page if I want to click on this add to
cart button all the add to cart buttons
have got similar properties and Tosca
cannot identify and cannot perform the
click on this so let's see this in
action and then we'll see how we can
resolve this issue
so let me go back to Tosca and here I'm
going to scan this particular
application and add this particular
button into our module
so let's do that first
I'm going to select this application
here
and then uh here we will see that there
are different add to cart buttons and if
I go ahead and select one of these you
will see that the item is not unique
right so selected item is not unique and
if I go into properties even in the
technical properties you won't find any
property which will help you to identify
this uniquely okay so as I said uh you
can always go ahead and use this
different identification mechanisms like
anchor image or index in order to make
this unique right but what if I don't
want to do this okay so let's go ahead
and save this module first
and let's close this let's go back to
our Tosca
and here I am quickly going to rename
this okay so I'm going to call it
products
and now I have created a test case here
uh with a folder so here I'm going to
add this particular module okay so let
me drag this to here and this will
create meta step okay
and we are just performing uh add to cut
so I'm going to perform the click method
on this add to cart button okay so first
uh let's go ahead and run this and let's
see if it can actually perform the click
or not and what is the error which is
written by Tosca
so as soon as you see that Tosca is
taking some time to perform any
particular action and it is doing
nothing that means uh it is a sign that
you are going to face some error okay
because then it goes into that timeout
phase where you have mentioned some time
out some default timeout for identifying
a particular element right so if it is
fails to identify that in that
particular timeout then after that time
it is going to return a particular error
okay
so now um as you can see uh the test
case has failed and if I go back to
Tosca
here it will exactly tell you what has
happened okay so in the login for you
will see that more than one control
found okay for this action
now as I said there are multiple ways of
handling this particular scenario right
you can do it at the module level but I
want to show you another way which is
possible okay
so for this uh what we need to do is we
need to go to our module and go to this
module attribute and here we need to add
another configuration parameter okay so
when you right click and click on create
configuration parameter here I am going
to add another configuration parameter
called explicit name
okay and we can set this value
to either true false or we can also
provide a range okay and then in the
test case you can use any particular
name from that range or if it is set to
true then you can use
um some other name through which it can
probably steer that particular element
okay
so now if I go back to my test case here
I can actually change this name okay
so in normal scenarios if you don't have
that explicit name property or
configuration parameter then you cannot
change this name right from your test
case level right you can change it at a
module attribute level but you cannot
change it at a test step level okay so
for this uh what I'm going to do is I'm
going to name it as hash okay and three
so what I'm telling Tosca is uh go ahead
and click on the number three button
okay in this particular page so it will
click on this add to cut
right and it is going to identify it
using this particular explicit name
property which we have uh provided for
this model attribute okay
so let's go ahead and run this now
and as you can see it is clicking on the
third add to cart button okay so
similarly you can steer any particular
element okay if there are some common
elements on the page maybe it is links
it is buttons or it is any other
elements right which where you want to
perform some action so you can steer it
this way okay so you just have to use
the explicit name property for that
module attribute and then put a name uh
as the number of the element which you
are trying to perform the action on it
is similar to uh index property right
where we provide an index of a
particular element but this would be
more stable compared to index because
index as you know can change in a
particular page right
so that's all for this particular video
I hope you enjoyed it and learned
something new today don't forget to
subscribe to our Channel as a VR
regularly posting new videos and you
would want to get notified every time we
post a new video okay
also if you have any other suggestions
or any other topic which you want to
learn just put it on the comments and
we'll make sure that uh we would include
that in the coming up sessions so until
we meet again keep enjoying our sessions
on Tosca and keep learning